<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RC Cars: a primer on Self-driving RC Car</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RC Cars: a primer on Self-driving RC Car</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/rc-car/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Parts: an overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/parts_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/parts_list/</guid>
      <description>There’s a lot of, and I mean a lot of parts when it comes to building an RC car on your own. But in the context of building a self-driving RC car, here’s a brief overview of some of the stuff we’ll need:&#xA;You&amp;rsquo;ll want to have: A RC car (with some batteries) A PWM/Servo Driver (I2C + some jumper cables) A Jetson Nano A powerbank (+ some usb cables) A microSD card (and optionally an external SSD) A WiFi/BT m.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scale</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/scale/</guid>
      <description>&#xD;Most RC cars are scaled down versions of their real-life equivalent, so they&amp;rsquo;re expressed in ratios, the most common ones being (real-life size : RC model size):&#xA;1:18 1:16 1:10 1:8 there are also all sorts of scales in between those (and above/below) Of course, the question is: why do we care, and what&amp;rsquo;s better for a self-driving RC car?&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty simple:&#xA;a bigger RC car equals more real estate and more power to carry all of our gadgets on top of it, without damaging the motors while struggling with all of the weight, but a bigger car needs a bigger race track and road size we want to drive it on </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RC Car body types</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/body_type/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/body_type/</guid>
      <description>The best body type for on road self-driving purposes is the standard race body type.&#xA;But to be thorough, we could roughly group all of the RC cars in 4 distinct categories:&#xA;RACE/STREET Probably the first thing that comes to mind when thinking of an RC car, a standard race car. This body type is the fastest and the best on paved, flat surfaces and is meant for on road use only.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electric motors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/electric_motors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/electric_motors/</guid>
      <description>The main question concerning electric motors is: brushed or brushless? Brushed pros: cheaper, simpler, better for off-road.&#xA;Brushed cons: heavier, bigger, worse power efficiency (75-80%), they wear out in time.&#xA;Brushless pros: long lifespan, much better speed and handling, better power efficiency (85-90%).&#xA;Brushless cons: much more expensive, worse for off-road.&#xA;So what should we get? It depends on your budget, but brushed motors work just fine, and besides, for self-driving purposes, you don’t need a RC car that drives 100 KPH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steering servo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/servo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/servo/</guid>
      <description>An RC servo is used for controlling the steering wheels of the car. It almost always comes with the RC car, so you shouldn’t worry about getting one.&#xA;It typically expects around 4.8V to 6V input on the power wire (varies by car) and a PWM control signal on the signal wire. Typically, the three wires are colored black-red-white, or brown-red-yellow, where:&#xA;the dark wire (black/brown) is ground, and the center wire (red) is power, and the light wire (white/yellow) is control.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Speed Controller</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/electronic_speed_controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/electronic_speed_controller/</guid>
      <description>The role of the ESC is to take a RC PWM control signal (pulse between 1000 and 2000 microseconds) in, and use that to control the power to the motor so the motor spins with different amounts of power in forward or reverse. Many RC car kits come with an ESC preinstalled, in which case you should be just fine.&#xA;Again, 1500 microseconds typically means &amp;ldquo;center&amp;rdquo; which for the motor means &amp;ldquo;dead stop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Receiver</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/receiver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/receiver/</guid>
      <description>If you buy a &amp;ldquo;kit car&amp;rdquo; that is listed as &amp;ldquo;needs a receiver,&amp;rdquo; then you don&amp;rsquo;t need to buy a receiver.&#xA;The Jetson Nano and the PWM/Servo driver will replace the receiver, outputting control signals to the car. If you’re buying a kit with a steering servo, motor, and ESC, you should actually try to not get a receiver, since the RC car could be specifically designed for that receivers PWM signals, and you’ll be taking it apart anyways.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Batteries</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/batteries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/rc-car/batteries/</guid>
      <description>There are two types of batteries used for RC cars: Nickel Metal Hydride batteries (NiMH) and Lithium Polymer batteries (LiPo).&#xA;TL;DR: LiPo batteries are much better, but also more expensive.&#xA;Lithium Polymer batteries generally have higher current capacity (the amount of Amps the battery can deliver at one point while driving) as well as energy storage (the number of Amp Hours the battery stores when fully charged) so it may also last longer.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
